CHRISTOPHER MULVEY DATA SCIENTIST

SUMMARY

Over a 21 year career with the US Navy, I became interested in the way data is handled. When an opportunity to change careers arose, I saw a chance to explore that interest and make it my new career. I am a seasoned, accomplished leader and pilot with proven expertise managing complex programs and projects serving mission-critical objectives and in support of distributed customers / stakeholders.

Core competencies include:

- Data Analysis with Excel(Advanced) and SQL(Postgres)
- Git and GitHub
- Agile and Kanban
- Python/Pandas

- R/DPlyr
- Tableau
- PowerBI
- Change and Risk Management
- Workflow and Process Redesign

DATA ANALYST EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School, Nashville, Tennessee

Apprentice Data Scientist, 9/2021 to 6/2022

- Nine month part-time introduction to the data science process and toolset. Emphasis on learning and practice in getting and organizing data, exploratory data analysis, building models and testing hypotheses, machine learning, data visualization and storytelling using Python, R, and SQL.
 - o Midstone Explored Emergency Room spending in the US through an R Shiny app. Data processed using R and DPlyr and visualized in R Shiny.
 - o Emergency Department Healthcare Spending In US 2006-2016

Apprentice Data Analyst, 9/2020 to 1/2021

- Four month full-time intensive introduction to data analytics and business intelligence processes and tools. Emphasis on analytical reasoning through hands-on training on every stage of the analytics workflow.
 - Capstone An analysis of the impact of COVID-19 on the U.S. airline industry. Data was webscraped using Python. Exploratory data analysis done in Python and Excel. Visualizations done in Tableau.
 - o Capstone on Tableau Public
- Tools: SQL(Postgres), Excel(Advanced), Python, PowerBI, and Tableau

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Huron Consulting Group, Remote

Enterprise Solutions & Analytics Consulting Associate, 1/2021 to Present

- Create custom data queries and reports for clients to derive insights that cannot be gained from Perception Health's TEAM platform.
- Use SQL, Python, and Excel daily to extract and analyze medical claims data.
- Dashboarding with Amazon Quicksight
- Utilize AWS S3, Athena, and Cloud9 daily

Perception Health, Franklin, Tennessee

Health Analyst, 2/2021 to 12/2021

- Created custom data queries and reports for clients to derive insights that cannot be gained from Perception Health's TEAM platform.
- Used SQL, Python, and Excel daily to extract and analyze medical claims data.
- JIRA and Google chat used for daily communications

Trans States Airlines, St Louis, Missouri

Embraer 145 First Officer, 6/2018 to 4/2020

• Embraer 145 First Officer for a regional airline based at Chicago O'Hare International Airport.

US Navy, 5/1997 to 8/2018

Leonardo, New Jersey

Senior Operations Manager, 10/2015 to 7/2018

- Serving as Commanding Officer, oversaw Navy Operational Support Center Earle and a staff of 17 supporting 230 Navy Selected Reservists.
- Responsible for \$700K annual budget, as well as security and maintenance of 3 Navy Operational Support Center Earle facilities, and 2 vehicles.
- Ensured information security and policy / regulatory compliance, including HIPAA and PII.
- Seamlessly planned, orchestrated, and oversaw 12 annual Reserve weekends, coordinated travel, lodging, and meals for 100-200 Reservists; scheduled all training sessions and speakers, tracked completed training requirements, processed travel expense claims, and managed Reserve duty payroll.
- Improved command performance and morale after previous Commanding Officer was relieved, garnering improved scores for command climate surveys.

Millington, Tennessee

Program Manager, 2/2014 to 9/2015

- Directed \$35M Active Duty for Special Work (ADSW) Program within Navy Personnel Command, leading team of 8 personnel, in production of 1.5K official orders per year.
- Regularly worked with widely distributed organizations to define staffing requirements and clarify official orders.
- Played instrumental role in command-level business process reengineering initiative.
- Spearheaded overhaul of ADSW governing instruction.
- Lead transition from paper-based to electronic workflows within the ADSW program.

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

Data Science Boot Camp

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL, Nashville, Tennessee, June 2022

Data Analytics Boot Camp

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL, Nashville, Tennessee, January 2021

Master of Science in Information Technology Project Management

UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND UNIVERSITY COLLEGE, Adelphi, Maryland, Attended 2016 – 2017 Completed 18 credits toward degree

Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems

NORWICH UNIVERSITY, Northfield, Vermont

Security Clearance: Secret (out of scope 2/2018)

Top Secret application completed but not adjudicated because of retirement

Licensure & Certification: CompTIA A+, Network+, and Security+ Certifications

Professional Development: US Navy Flight School – fixed & rotary wing